JAYALAKSHMI GNANAPRAKASAM

Handphone: +91 960015 8641

E-Mail id: jayalakshmidino00@gmail.com

Address: #35/69, A.E. Kovil Street, Valluvar Nagar, Chennai-81, TN, India

Education

Bachelor of Engineering (B.E) -Electronics and Communication Engineering (ECE), Sriram Engineering College, IN, 2013

Languages

English - Fluent Tamil - Fluent

Technical Skills

Primary skill set: Data Testing, SQL, and UNIX

Tools: Toad, Oracle SQL Developer, DB2, QuerySurge, JIRA, HP-ALM, Informatica, DataStage, Control-M, OPC and Oozie

Databases: Oracle, Hive, DB2, SQL Server

Technologies: Data Warehousing, Hadoop, Agile

Certifications

QuerySurge Practitioner Certification QuerySurge ETL Tester Certification IBM certified Cloud Advocate Big Data foundational Certification Hadoop Foundational Certification

Profile

To work in a globally competitive environment on challenging assignments that shall yield the benefits of job satisfaction and a steady paced professional growth.

9 years' experience in QA manual testing with the intent of improving software quality, exceeding client expectations, and implementing process improvement methods.

Work experience

Test Specialist - Data

IBM, India | Mar 2015 - Present

- An accomplished QA Tester with extensive experience in project management, business analysis, requirements definition, software testing and quality assurance.
- Strong Test management capability to ensure quality and timely delivery with optimum resource utilization.
- Knowledge of complete Software test life cycle (SDLC) and Agile Testing with expertise in various testing methodologies and quality assurance techniques
- Well versed in designing **Test Strategy**, **Test Plan**, **Test Scenario**, **Reviews**, and **Execution with reporting to all management**
- Involved in Documenting the **test cases**, **test scripts**, **pre-test conditions**, input data, actual data and expected results for system integration testing.
- Heavily involved in Data testing, Ad-hoc, Functional, Unit, Integration, Regression, End to End, System Integration SIT and User Acceptance UAT, Smoke Testing/Build Acceptance Testing, Black Box and White Box Testing in databases and various applications.
- **Log, track, and verify resolution** of software and specification defects along with documenting all phases of QA process.
- Managed various QA phases, Train, and mentor team members on process/test methods.
- Test Automation using **QuerySurge tool version 8.0 and 9.0.**
- Used Reporting tool JIRA and HP-ALM for defect tracking and management.
- Exposure in TOSCA BI, Cloud Computing and Power Query.

Assignment history

Senior test Specialist - IBM, India | Apr 2020 - Oct 2021 **Project name:** Bank of America - PB Trust M2M - IS1, Extract & Migrate

Contribution:

- Performed Automation Data testing using QuerySurge tool to validate the ETL mapping logics in transformation layer based on the business requirement.
- Testing Phase completed ahead of the estimated time which reduced cost and increased productivity for the project.
- Automated mock up data creation in QuerySurge tool which reduced the manual tasks and time saved.

- Enhanced the identification of high-risk defects and loopholes in the project by running multiple query pairs and snippets using QuerySurge based on the new requirements.
- Involved in User Acceptance Testing and Provided AMS On-call support.
- Expertise in QuerySurge and Bug Reporting tool JIRA.

Test Specialist - IBM, India | May 2019 - Mar 2020

Project name: CYBG - Virgin Money - Modern Data Environment Project

Contribution:

- Developed Query pairs, snippets, and connections in Query Surge to validate the objects in extract layer.
- Designed multiple query pairs in transformation layer to validate the mapping logic and identified the high-risk defects.
- Performed End to End ETL testing.
- Expertise in QuerySurge and Bug Reporting tool JIRA.
- Proficient in functional, negative, regression, system integration (SIT), acceptance (UAT), load/performance, security.
- Handled database testing by using Hive and Postgres.
- Given Playback session to the vendors and KT session to the teammates.

Data Engineer - IBM, India | Apr 2017 - Jun 2018

Project name: PayPal Inc - PFiT-FETL

Contribution:

- Code review and SQL tuning.
- Reviewed new requests and changed the existing mapping based on the business requirements.
- Designed mappings and transformations using Informatica tool.
- Solely responsible for project related migrations and deployments to QA and production environments.
- Handled production problem tickets and issue resolution.
- Performed maintenance of production system
- Assured to meet daily SLA for all mart related loads.

Senior Technical Operator - IBM, India | Nov 2015 - Mar 2017

Project name: Hertz - Hertz Production control

Contribution: Shift Lead in production control

- Worked as a shift lead in production control.
- Performed following Activities in Mainframe- Monitoring Jobs, Reporting Abends, Fixing Abends, Spool Monitoring, System Health Check, Processing SDSF, SAVER.
- Performed Schedule Changes for Jobs in a day today Process and one-time schedule for UNIX Jobs.
- Performed Adhoc requests and IPL on all L-pars.
- Escalated issues to client and support team.
- Monitored the Net View alerts and responding to Console alerts actively.
- Documented the Reports in Tracker as a Daily process and reporting to client.
- Managed Multiple accounts.

Technical Operator - IBM, India | Mar 2015 - Mar 2017

Project name: MACY'S- MACY'S Production Control

Contribution:

- Performed following Activities in Mainframe- Monitoring Jobs, Reporting Abends, Fixing Abends, Spool Monitoring, System Health Check, Processing SDSF, SAVER.
- Performed Schedule Changes for Jobs in a day today Process and one-time schedule for UNIX Jobs.
- Performed Adhoc requests and IPL on all L-pars.
- Escalated issues to client and support team.
- Monitored the Net View alerts and responding to Console alerts actively.
- Documented the Reports in Tracker as a Daily process and reporting to client.
- Managed Multiple accounts.

Web Developer – Energy Alternatives India, India | Jan 2014 - Mar 2015 **Project name:** Clixoo – EAI websites

Contribution:

- Designed user interfaces and navigation menus.
- Developed codes for websites using PHP, HTML, XML, JavaScript.
- Integrated multimedia content on a site
- Performed testing on web applications.
- Troubleshooting problems with performance or user experience